Guide to the James Joyce collection, [ca. 1893]-1941
Joyce, James collection, [ca. 1893]-1941
- Series IV. Incoming Correspondence, Manuscripts and Documents
  - Alphabetical name index, L - Ph
    - C. A. Penrose (Box 11)
    - Pavlos Phocas (2) (Box 11)
  - Alphabetical name index, Pi - Quinn
    - James Brand Pinker (50) (Box 12)
    - James Brand Pinker to Nora Joyce (Box 12)
    - Ezra Loomis Pound (56) (Box 12)
    - Ezra Loomis Pound to Nora Joyce (4) (Box 12)
    - Ezra Loomis Pound to Mrs. W. A. Bradley (2) (Box 12)
    - Ezra Loomis Pound to George H. Healey (Box 12)
    - J. J. Power [?] (Box 12)
    - Roberto Prezioso (6) (Box 12)
    - Henry Blackwood Price (5) (Box 12)
    - Provincial Cinematograph Theaters, Ltd. (2) (Box 12)
    - The development of Joyce's image of women, MA Thesis, Valerie A. Purcel, Dec. 1984. (Box 12)
    - John Quinn (11) (Box 12)
    - John Quinn to Ezra Loomis Pound (5) (Box 12)
    - John Quinn to Nora Joyce (2) (Box 12)
    - John Quinn to Ben W. Huebsch [copy] (2) (Box 12)
  - Alphabetical name index, R - Sc
    - A. F. Ralli (3) (Box 13)
    - Rascher and Cie (Box 13)
    - Forrest Reid (Box 13)
    - F. Reventlow (2) (Box 13)
    - Grant Richards (49) (Box 13)
    - Mrs. B. Richardson to Israel Kaplan (Box 13)
    - Ercole Rivalta to Roberto Prezioso (Box 13)
    - Alston Rivers, Ltd. (Walter Levear) (Box 13)
    - Dr. Jacques Riviere (5) (Box 13)
    - George Roberts (13) (Box 13)
    - A Portrait of Oliver Gogarty, by W.R. Rodgers. Transcription of Radio transmission. (Box 13)
    - Robert Ross (Box 13)
    - Rettore Rossi (Box 13)
    - Royal Literary Fund (A. Llewelyn Roberts) (8) (Box 13)
    - Attestation of graduation of James Joyce [copy] (Box 13)
    - Paul Ruggiero (4) (Box 13)
    - W.F. Ryan (Box 13)
    - E. St. Leger (4) (Box 13)
    - Nicolas Santas (Box 13)
    - The Saturday Evening Post (Box 13)
    - Eileen Joyce Schaurek (3) (Box 13)
    - Eileen Joyce Schaurek to Nora Joyce (Box 13)
    - Franz Schaurek (8) (Box 13)
    - Schauspielhaus (2) (Box 13)
    - Ettore Schmitz (Italo Svevo) (4) (Box 13)
    - Charles E. Schmolder (Box 13)
    - Oscar Daniele Schwarz (Box 13)
  - Alphabetical name index, Se - Z
    - Martin Secker (Box 14)
    - J. C. Segrue (3) (Box 14)
    - Henry Blackman Sell to B. W. Huebsch (Box 14)
    - Mrs. Olivia Shakespear (Box 14)
    - George Bernard Shaw to Sylvia Beach [copy] (Box 14)
    - Hannah Sheehy (Box 14)
    - Francis Sheehy-Skeffington (2) (Box 14)
    - Tullio Silvestri (Box 14)
    - Bill from Singer Societa for a sewing machine, 1910 (Box 14)
    - Sisley's (Box 14)
    - Skandinavisk Teater Bureau (2) (Box 14)
    - Isaia Sonne (Box 14)
    - South African Colonisation Society (Florence Saunders) (Box 14)
    - The Speaker (4) (Box 14)
    - J. Browning Spence (2) (Box 14)
    - Margaret Spicer-Simson (Box 14)
    - Theodore Spicer-Simson (Box 14)
    - J. C. Squire (Box 14)
    - John W. N. Sullivan (Box 14)
    - Kevin Sullivan to Edmund Clynes (3) (Box 14)
    - Claud W. Sykes (3) (Box 14)
    - Daisy Sykes to Nora Joyce (Box 14)
    - Arthur Symons (12) (Box 14)
    - Edward Synge (Box 14)
    - Calling card, John Millington Synge (Box 14)
    - Membership card, Societe Fraternelle d'Etudiants Protestants, John Millington Synge (Box 14)
    - Attilio Tamaro (Box 14)
    - Bernhard Tauchnitz (Box 14)
    - Bryceson Treharne (Box 14)
    - Fratelli Treves, Editori (Box 14)
    - James Tuohy (Box 14)
    - letter of recommendation for James Joyce from Universita de Popolo (Trieste) (Box 14)
    - Universita di Padova (2) (Box 14)
    - Sansone Venezian (Box 14)
    - Gioachino Veneziani (Box 14)
    - Nicolo Vidacovich (3) (Box 14)
    - Those Longlong Words in Finnegans Wake, Joseph Vogel (Box 14)
    - A. P. Watt (Box 14)
    - Harriet Shaw Weaver (60) (Box 14)
    - Harriet Shaw Weaver to Nora Joyce (Box 14)
    - Herbert George Wells (Box 14)
    - Herbert George Wells to Ezra Loomis Pound (Box 14)
    - Georg Wettstein (2) (Box 14)
    - Typescript of Wordsworth's "Tintern Abbey" bears a note in Stanislaus Joyce's hand (Box 14)
    - William Butler Yeats (9) (Box 14)
    - William Butler Yeats to Ezra Loomis Pound (Box 14)
    - Bills for piano moving and rental plus several statements from Luigi Zanoni (Box 14)
- Series V. Photographs and Miscellaneous
  - Photograph of James Joyce, ca. 1918 (Box 15, Folder 0101)
    Zurich. 1 leaf. Not in Scholes.
  - Photograph of James Joyce from N.Y. Post Library Review, Mar. 31, 1923 (Box 15, Folder 0105)
    New York. 1 leaf. Not in Scholes.
  - Photograph of Nora Joyce, 1918 (Box 15, Folder 0125)
    Zurich. 1 leaf. Verso: "Mrs. Nora Joyce in 'Riders to the Sea'." Not in Scholes.
  - Photographs of J. F. Byrne at the Joyce Exhibit (2), Apr. 1959 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Ithaca. 2 leaves. Not in Scholes.
  - Photograph of Unidentified girl about 4 years old, [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 2)
    1 leaf. Scholes 1435.
  - Photograph of Michael Healy (not positively identified), [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Galway. 1 leaf. Scholes 1427.
  - Photograph, A wedding picture of Charles Joyce with his wife, [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 4)
    1 leaf. Scholes 1421.
  - Photograph of Charles Joyce with his wife and his first son, ca. 1911 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    1 leaf. Scholes 1422.
  - Photograph of Mrs. Charles Joyce, with small child, in front of a small frame house, [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Probably taken in the United States. 1 leaf. Scholes 1423.
  - Photograph of Mrs. Charles Joyce with her mother and first son, ca. 1913 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    1 leaf. Scholes 1424.
  - Photograph of Eva Joyce sitting at a small table, with a book [3 copies], [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 8)
    3 leaves. Not in Scholes.
  - Photograph of Eva and Lucia Joyce, ca. 1910 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Trieste. 1 leaf. Scholes 1425.
  - Photograph of Unidentified, possibly Giorgio Joyce, ca. 1911 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    1 leaf. Scholes 1433.
  - Photograph of James Joyce [3 copies], ca. 1930 [?] (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Photograph of Unidentified, possibly Nora Joyce, sitting, with head on hand, [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 12)
    1 leaf. Scholes 1432.
  - Photograph of Stanislaus Joyce [5 copies], [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 13)
    5 leaves. Not in Scholes.
  - Photograph of Thomas M. Kettle, in legal robes and wig, [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 14)
    Reproduced in Trieste, probably from a newspaper clipping. Not a good likeness according to J. F. Byrne. Scholes 1426.
  - Picture postcard of John. C. McCormick, [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 15)
    1 leaf. Scholes 1428.
  - Photograph of Mrs. Josephine Murray and three daughters, [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 16)
    1 leaf. Scholes 1430.
  - Photograph of Katsie Murray [3 copies], [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Photograph of Franz Schaurek and Eileen Joyce Schaurek, a wedding picture, 1915 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    Trieste. 1 leaf. Scholes 1429.
  - Photograph of two sisters of James Joyce and daughter of Josephine Murray, [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 19)
    1 leaf. Scholes 1431.
  - Photograph of unidentified Woman and teenaged daughter, [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 20)
    Galway. 1 leaf. Scholes 1434.
  - Photograph of unidentified Young woman, [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Photograph of unidentified Young woman, [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 22)
    Florence. 1 leaf. Scholes 1436.
  - Group of photographs of homes of Joyce family in Dublin [4photographs], 1960 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    Dublin. 4 leaves. Not in Scholes.
  - Group of labeled envelopes describing contents of Joyce papers in possession of Mrs. Stanislaus Joyce. [8 envelopes], [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 24)
    8 envelopes. Not in Scholes.
  - Unidentified material [3 items], [n.d.] (Box 15, Folder 25)
    3 leaves. 1 colored graph, not labeled; 1 note in pencil, unsigned, referring to "Giles" and "Mr M"; 1 sheet of Spanish poems, with translations into English, all in the same hand. Not in Scholes.
  - Photograph of 7 Eccles Street, Dublin, home of Joyce's friend J. F. Byrne and address of Leopold Bloom in Ulysses, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    Dublin. 1 leaf. Not in Scholes.
  - Book review by Robert M. Adams of Nora: The Real Life of Molly Bloom, by Brenda Maddox [copy], June 30, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    New York Review of Books. 3 leaves. Not in Scholes.
  - "The Scandal of Ulysses" John Kidd [copy], June 30, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    New York Review of Books. 15 leaves. Not in Scholes.
  - Dubliners Theatre Program, The Acting Company, directed by Paul Walker, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Ulysses: Film Souvenir Program, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    14 leaves bound. Photographs and commentary about film version of Ulysses. Not in Scholes.
  - Drawings (Box 16)